interpol.int 2019-03-31

# Privacy policy

### About this site

INTERPOL’s Website (the “Site”) provides information about the Organization and our activities and provides access to certain services. To ensure the effective functioning of the Site and provision of these services, personal data are collected from you (the “User”) when you access the Site.

### What is the scope of this Privacy Policy?

This Privacy Policy explains what types of personal data we collect from Users of the Site, how we process that data and for which purposes. In addition, the Policy explains how Users can exercise their rights regarding personal data that was collected through the Site.

### What is personal data?

“Personal data” is any data about an identified natural person or a person who may be identified by means that may reasonably be used.

For example, your name and email address can be considered personal data.

### Do we collect personal data of our Site Users?

We collect personal data when you access the Site and its services in two ways:

 **Data we collect through your use of the Site**

As you browse the Site or use the services on our Site, personal data is collected to ensure the effective functioning of the Site and the provision of services. We collect the following types of personal data:

  *  **Log information**

This includes data on the way you use our services, such as the web pages you visit, the time and date of your visit as well as your internet protocol (IP) address.

  *  **Device and browser information**

This includes data on your device and browser specifications, such as the type of operating system and version, browser type and language settings.

The processing of this data is based on the legitimate interest of the Organization to collect statistics on the use of the Site and monitor the Site and services for network and information security purposes.

In addition, log, device and browser information may be used to assess the reliability of messages sent by Users to INTERPOL. If the message is not intended for purposes of international police cooperation, this information will immediately be deleted. 

  *  **Cookie information**

The Site uses cookies that may collect personal data for statistics, online form submissions and when third party services are embedded on the Site, such as videos and social media buttons. You can control these cookies in your browser settings.

For more information on the Site’s use of cookies, please see our Cookie Policy.

 **Data you provide to us**

The Site allows you to directly provide us with personal data either by filling out a form on the Site or by registering for one of our services on the Site.

 ** _By filling out a form on the Site_**

Users can contact INTERPOL by filling out a form on the Site. In doing so, you may provide INTERPOL with:

  *  **Contact details**

Some forms may require an email address to be filled out, but any other personal data you provide is voluntary.

  *  **Personal data about you**

As the forms include a free text field, you may provide further personal data about yourself in your message or in attachment. The provision of such personal data is voluntary.

By providing us with such data, you consent with our processing of that data. Your contact details may be used to respond to your message. However, we will not pass this data on to other parties without your prior consent.

In addition, your message may also contain:

  *  **Other information**

As the forms include a free text field, you may provide personal data about other individuals in your message or in attachment, for instance information on wanted fugitives. The provision of such personal data is voluntary.

 ** _By registering for a specific service_**

There are certain services accessible through the Site for which you need to register, such as the recruitment or procurement platform.

As these services are provided for a specific purpose, such as recruitment, you will find more information related to the data protection policies of those specific services prior to registering. 

### How do we process your personal data?

The personal data we collect through your use of the Site is processed in accordance with the following principles:

  *  **Lawful processing**

We process your personal data based on your consent or in the legitimate interest of the Organization, as explained in this Privacy Policy.

  *  **Purpose limitatio** n

We only process your personal data for the purposes listed in this Privacy Policy.

  *  **Data quality**

We conduct quality checks on the data we receive to assess whether it is accurate, relevant, up to date and not excessive in relation to the purpose for which it was collected.

  *  **Transparency**

We process your personal data in a transparent manner by keeping you informed on why and how we process your data as well as the means by which you can exercise your rights.

  *  **Confidentiality**

We will not disclose your personal data to third parties without your prior consent, unless specific circumstances arise under which we would consider ourselves required to do so (see below).

  *  **Security**

We keep your data secure by protecting it against risks which may violate its integrity and confidentiality.

  *  **Data Subject Rights**

You have the right to access, correct and delete your personal data. These rights are further clarified in this Privacy Policy.

### How long do we store your personal data?

We store your personal data, collected through your use of the Site and data you provide to us, for an initial period of five years or until the purpose for which the data was collected has been reached.

###  Do we disclose your personal data?

As a general rule, we will not forward your personal data to third parties without your prior consent. Nevertheless, there may be circumstances under which we consider ourselves required to disclose your personal data for:

  * the protection of your vital interests as well as those of other individuals;
  * the establishment, exercise or defence of the Organization against any legal claims or allegations; or
  * the protection and integrity of the Site and the services provided through the Site.

### How do we process data for purposes of international police cooperation?

If the data you provide pertains to information on criminal activities, threats or wanted fugitives, the data will be processed by the relevant crime units and/or forwarded to the National Central Bureau(s) of the countries concerned. We will process this data in accordance with INTERPOL’s Rules on the Processing of Data

  *  **What are your rights as a data subject?**

Your rights, as a data subject, in the context of police cooperation are set out in several of INTERPOL’s legal instruments, including:

  * INTERPOL’s Constitution;
  * INTERPOL’s Rules on the Processing of Data;
  * Statute of The Commission for the Control of INTERPOL’s Files.

The Commission for the Control of INTERPOL’s Files is an independent oversight body. You are entitled, in the context of police cooperation, to file an application to access, correct or delete your personal data.

For more information on the Commission for the Control of INTERPOL’s Files, please visit their webpage.

If your request pertains to a service on the Site for which you have registered, such as the recruitment portal, you may be able to access, amend and delete your personal data through the service.

### What happens when you click on a link to a third party website or application?

When you click on a link that redirects you to a third party website or application, such as our social media channels, INTERPOL is not responsible for the collection of your personal data on that website or application.

As a consequence, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and we would advise you to familiarize yourself with the privacy policy of the website or application you are accessing.

### How will you be informed of updates to this Policy?

In the event that we modify or update this Privacy Policy, we will clearly indicate the date of modification or update.

Changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately when this page is published.

If an update to the Privacy Policy pertains to a significant change to the way in which we process your personal data, we will provide you with a reasonable amount of time to assess the updated Privacy Policy and its impact prior to the Policy taking effect.

### How can you contact us?

INTERPOL General Secretariat

200, quai Charles de Gaulle  
69006 Lyon  
France
